Aline Schneider

Boca Raton, FL 33486

aline.schv@gmail.com Phone: 561-283-9445 linkedin.com/in/aline-schneider github.com/alineschneider

Summary

Driven Data Analyst with a passion for translating data into insightful recommendations. With leadership experience, excels at both working independently as well as collaborating with teams. Skilled in Microsoft Excel, Python/Pandas/Numpy, SQL, Machine Learning and full-stack development. Strong data analysis professional with a certification focused in Data Analytics and Visualization from UC Berkeley.

Skills

Data Analysis
Python / Pandas / Numpy
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
R
Machine Learning
PostgreSQL
Tableau
Plotly visualizations
Flask
Microsoft Office

Certifications

Data Analytics and Visualization University of California Berkeley

March 2020 - August 2020



Education

Bachelor's in Civil Engineering
Federal University of Espírito Santo Vitória, Brazil
February 2005 - August 2010

Work Experience

Senior Optimization Analyst

HiConversion – Boca Raton - FL February 2019 - present

Lead the Optimization Analyst team, strategize A/B and multivariate testing for e-commerce websites to improve user experience and increase revenue; analyze the data; interpret results and present them to clients. Assist Sales department with presentations to prospective clients.

Budget and Finance Analyst

Brazilian Institute of Geography and Statistics - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil June 2014 - December 2017 (3 years 7 months)

IBGE is a Brazilian Federal Government institution; the role involved extracting, treating and analyzing data reports relative to financial expenses; registering and controlling warranties and security deposits by third party companies providing services to IBGE.

Administrative Analyst

Vale S.A. - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil August 2011 - September 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Vale is a Brazilian metals and mining corporation; I worked alongside a multidisciplinary team on a project, which included benchmarking visits and travelling to Vale's operation sites, identifying opportunities to improve productivity and providing tools for better visual management.